Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an elementary level lesson for you all about
我叫凯瑟琳，今天我们要为大家带来一堂初级水平的课程，内容是关于
getting up in the morning.
早上起床。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're making breakfast and well, of course, many people have different things
今天我们要做早餐，当然，很多人有不同的喜好。
when they're making breakfast.
当他们做早餐的时候。
Some of them are very big, others are small.
有些非常大，有些则很小。
So but this is what we're going to talk about today.
所以，这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue and see what they're having for breakfast today.
那我们不如来听听这段对话，看看他们今天早餐吃了什么。
Smells good.
闻起来真香。
What's for breakfast?
早餐吃什么？
Well, since we're getting up so late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
嗯，既然我们起得这么晚，我决定做一顿丰盛的早餐。
Nice.
好的。
Brunch.
早午餐。
Kind of.
算是吧。
So I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs, some French toast and buttermilk pancakes.
所以我做了炒蛋和溏心蛋，还有一些法式吐司和酪乳煎饼。
Wow, you really went all out.
哇，你真是全力以赴了。
Did you make any coffee?
你煮咖啡了吗？
Yeah, just the way you like it.
是啊，就按你喜欢的来。
I also put out some cereal and muesli if you feel like having something more light.
我还准备了麦片和什锦早餐，如果你想吃得清淡点的话。
Looks good.
看起来不错。
I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
我来榨点新鲜橙汁。
Get the jam and butter while you are in there.
你顺便把果酱和黄油拿过来。
Oh, and don't forget the syrup.
哦，别忘了糖浆。
All righty.
好的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting things.
所以有很多有趣的东西。
A huge breakfast.
一顿丰盛的早餐。
Way too big for me.
对我来说太多了。
I don't like to eat a big breakfast because I feel like it makes me tired and then I don't
我不喜欢早餐吃太多，因为我觉得那会让我犯困，然后我就没有
have any energy.
精力了。
Especially if you just get up, right?
尤其是刚起床的时候，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
You need to shower and maybe have some fruit and then go to work.
你需要洗个澡，吃点水果，然后去上班。
But we can talk about that at the end.
但我们可以在最后再聊这个。
There were a lot of interesting words and phrases that we heard that we would benefit
我们听到了很多有趣的单词和短语，值得
from taking a closer look at.
仔细看看。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so on Language Takeaway today, we're going to take a look at our first word
好的，今天在语言要点环节，我们先来看第一个词。
and it's an interesting word.
这是个有趣的词。
It's kind of a mix of two things.
它有点像两种东西的混合。
Brunch.
早午餐。
That's right.
没错。
So this word comes from two different words.
所以这个词来自两个不同的词。
Breakfast, b-b-breakfast and lunch.
早餐，早——早餐和午餐。
That's right.
没错。
So brunch.
所以就是早午餐。
So if you have brunch, what is exactly brunch?
那么如果你吃早午餐，早午餐到底是什么？
Well there's two ways to look at brunch.
嗯，有两种方式来看待早午餐。
One is the time element.
一个是时间因素。
Usually brunch is later than breakfast, but maybe a little earlier than lunch.
通常早午餐比早餐晚，但可能比午餐早一点。
So 11 o'clock or maybe even noon.
所以是11点，甚至可能是中午。
But the other thing is size.
但另一个方面是分量。
Because you're putting two meals together, usually brunch is very big.
因为你要把两餐合在一起，通常早午餐量很大。
You eat a lot of food.
你会吃很多食物。
Okay, so it's a perfect combination of breakfast and lunch.
好的，所以它是早餐和午餐的完美结合。
I'm the type of person that likes having scrambled eggs at noon.
我是那种喜欢中午吃炒蛋的人。
So this is a perfect solution, brunch.
所以这是个完美的解决方案，早午餐。
Right, you don't have to only eat eggs at breakfast, you can eat them at lunch as well.
没错，你不必只在早餐吃鸡蛋，午餐也可以吃。
Exactly.
没错。
This is actually something we do a lot in America for Mother's Day.
这其实是我们美国人在母亲节经常做的事情。
So mom wakes up late, we take her to brunch.
所以妈妈晚起，我们带她去吃早午餐。
It's a very big special meal.
这是一顿非常丰盛的大餐。
Very good.
非常好。
And talking about eggs and the types of eggs that we can have, I mentioned scrambled eggs
说到鸡蛋以及我们能吃的鸡蛋种类，我提到了炒蛋，
and in the dialogue we also heard soft-boiled eggs.
在对话中我们还听到了水煮蛋。
Okay, these are two very important kinds of eggs.
好的，这是两种非常重要的鸡蛋做法。
Usually if you're in a restaurant, they will ask you how do you want your eggs cooked or
通常如果你在餐厅，他们会问你想怎么煮鸡蛋，
done.
或者怎么做。
And my answer is always scrambled.
而我的答案总是炒蛋。
This means someone mixes the eggs before they are cooked and then when they cook, they are
这意味着有人在鸡蛋煮熟前把它们搅拌好，然后煮的时候，
hard, they're yellow.
它们会变硬，呈黄色。
There's no white, it's just yellow and it's a little hard mixture.
没有蛋白，只有黄色，是一种有点硬的混合物。
But soft-boiled eggs are very, very different.
但水煮蛋非常非常不同。
That's right, soft-boiled eggs, you actually don't break the egg or open the egg to cook
没错，水煮蛋，你实际上不用像炒蛋那样打破鸡蛋或打开蛋壳来煮，
it like in scrambled eggs.
就像炒蛋那样。
You actually put the entire egg in boiling water.
你实际上是把整个鸡蛋放进沸水里。
I think it's for two minutes and then you take it out and then you open the shell and
我想是煮两分钟，然后拿出来，再打开蛋壳，
the eggs are kind of cooked, it's kind of hard in some parts but it's also kind of liquidy
鸡蛋有点熟了，有些部分有点硬，但也有些部分还是液态的。
in other parts.
在其他地方。
That's right.
没错。
So the outside, the white part is hard but the yellow part, the yolk is liquid.
所以外面白色的部分是硬的，但黄色的蛋黄是液态的。
It's not hard.
它不硬。
That's right.
没错。
And actually if you want the whole egg to be hard, you can ask for hard-boiled eggs.
实际上，如果你想让整个鸡蛋都变硬，可以点煮鸡蛋。
That's right, those are cooked for much longer.
没错，那些煮的时间更长。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we have scrambled eggs, soft-boiled eggs, we have French toast and we have buttermilk
好的，我们有炒蛋、溏心蛋、法式吐司和酪乳
pancakes.
煎饼。
Okay, so you can ask for just pancakes.
好的，所以你可以直接点煎饼。
But if you want to be specific, you want to give instructions about what kind of pancakes,
但如果你想具体点，想说明要哪种煎饼，
you can ask for buttermilk pancakes.
你可以点酪乳煎饼。
And what exactly is buttermilk?
酪乳到底是什么？
Buttermilk is a very, very creamy, eggy milk that's very, very high in fat that makes everything
酪乳是一种非常非常奶油状、蛋味浓郁的牛奶，脂肪含量非常高，能让所有东西
taste better, I think.
味道更好，我觉得。
This is used a lot in baking, not really in other kinds of foods.
这在烘焙中常用，其他食物中不太用。
So you can have buttermilk muffins or buttermilk biscuits.
所以你可以有酪乳松饼或酪乳饼干。
But usually you have buttermilk pancakes and so these are very rich, very fatty pancakes.
但通常你吃的是酪乳煎饼，这些是非常浓郁、高脂肪的煎饼。
Awesome, yeah, they taste delicious.
太棒了，是的，它们味道很好。
Alright, so now if we want to eat a little bit more healthy, we do have some cereal and
好了，现在如果我们想吃得更健康一点，我们有一些麦片和
some muesli.
什锦麦片。
Muesli is a funny word, it's not a sound we make very often in English.
Muesli 是个有趣的词，在英语中不常听到。
Muesli.
Muesli。
Yeah.
是的。
I think it actually comes from German.
我觉得它其实来自德语。
It does look German.
看起来确实像德语。
Because actually the spelling is M-U-E, so you would kind of want to say Muesli or something.
因为拼写是 M-U-E，所以你会想读成 Muesli 之类的。
Yeah, no, we say Muesli and it's basically a mixture of granola or different kinds of
是的，不，我们说 Muesli，它基本上是格兰诺拉麦片或不同种类的
fiber grains.
纤维谷物的混合物。
So just think of having raisins and maybe some almonds, granola, all mixed up and you
所以想象一下有葡萄干、可能还有杏仁、格兰诺拉麦片，全部混合在一起，你
have this nice thing that goes well with yogurt, muesli.
就有了这个和酸奶很配的好东西，Muesli。
It's very, very tasty and also very good for you.
非常非常好吃，而且对你身体也很好。
And now, well, actually going back to pancakes, no pancake is possible to eat unless you put
现在，嗯，实际上回到煎饼，没有煎饼能不加
syrup on it, right?
糖浆就吃，对吧？
Well, some people might disagree.
嗯，有些人可能不同意。
I know a lot of people who eat pancakes with honey or with butter.
我知道很多人吃煎饼加蜂蜜或黄油。
But the best, I think, is with syrup.
但我觉得最好的是加糖浆。
And syrup is basically liquid sugar and you put it on your pancakes to make them sweeter.
糖浆基本上是液态糖，你把它放在煎饼上让它们更甜。
Actually, it's the same thing as honey basically, except that it doesn't come from bees.
实际上，它和蜂蜜基本一样，只是不是来自蜜蜂。
Right, so real syrup, we say maple syrup, comes from maple trees and you tap the tree
对，真正的糖浆，我们叫枫糖浆，来自枫树，你 tapping 树
and it comes out.
它就流出来。
It's very, very, very sweet.
非常非常非常甜。
But we also have syrup you can buy at the store, which is man-made.
但我们也有在商店买的糖浆，是人造的。
Artificial.
人工的。
Yeah, it's basically just sugar.
是的，它基本上就是糖。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So that's what we have with pancakes usually.
所以煎饼通常配这个。
But why don't we go back, listen to our dialogue again.
但我们为什么不回去，再听一遍我们的对话。
Let's review all of these yummy breakfast treats and we'll come back in a bit with Fluency
让我们回顾所有这些美味的早餐食品，稍后我们会回来进行流利度
Builder.
训练。
Smells good.
闻起来真香。
What's for breakfast?
早餐吃什么？
Well, since we're getting up so late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
嗯，既然我们起得这么晚，我决定做一顿丰盛的早餐。
Nice, brunch.
不错，早午餐。
Kind of.
差不多吧。
So I made scrambled and soft-boiled eggs, some French toast, and buttermilk pancakes.
所以我做了炒蛋和溏心蛋，一些法式吐司，还有酪乳煎饼。
Wow, you really went all out.
哇，你真是全力以赴了。
Did you make any coffee?
你煮咖啡了吗？
Yeah, just the way you like it.
是的，按你喜欢的口味。
I also put out some cereal and muesli if you feel like having something more light.
我还放了一些麦片和什锦麦片，如果你想吃清淡点的话。
Looks good.
看起来不错。
I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
我来榨点新鲜橙汁。
Get the jam and butter while you are in there.
你去的时候拿果酱和黄油。
Oh, and don't forget the syrup.
哦，别忘了糖浆。
Alrighty.
好的。
All right, so now on Fluency Builder, why don't we take a look at a couple of phrases.
好了，现在在流利度训练中，我们来看看几个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
When the guy was kind of surprised, he said, wow, you really went all out.
当那个家伙有点惊讶时，他说，哇，你真是全力以赴了。
Okay, so this comes from the phrase, to go all out.
好的，这来自短语“to go all out”。
So he went all out or I'm going to go all out.
所以他全力以赴了，或者我要全力以赴。
And this means to give something your best, to do more than is expected.
这意味着尽最大努力，做得比预期更多。
That's right.
没错。
So if you go all out when you're making breakfast, it means you just, you cooked a lot or really
所以如果你做早餐时全力以赴，意味着你做了很多或做得
good and you spend a lot of time doing it.
非常好，花了很多时间。
Or for example, if it's someone's birthday and I know it's their birthday, I go all out
或者例如，如果是某人的生日，我知道是他们的生日，我会全力以赴
by buying gifts and a cake and lots of decorations and calling all of their friends and having
买礼物、蛋糕和很多装饰，叫上所有朋友，举办
a party.
派对。
So this is doing everything for them.
所以这是为他们做一切。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And he was really surprised and he really seemed to enjoy breakfast and he said, looks
他真的很惊讶，而且看起来非常享受早餐，他说，
good.
看起来不错。
Okay, this is a way to say good job or nicely done.
好的，这是一种说“做得好”或“干得漂亮”的方式。
It's almost a way to say, I'm happy about this.
这几乎是在说“我对这个很满意”。
Or yeah, and obviously you can also say that the food looks delicious, so it looks good.
或者，当然你也可以说食物看起来很好吃，所以“看起来不错”。
It looks good.
看起来不错。
So it's a way to say, you know, well done, looks good or in this case, looks very tasty.
所以这是一种表达“干得好，看起来不错”的方式，或者在这里是“看起来很好吃”。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And now this is an interesting part.
现在这是一个有趣的部分。
He says, I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
他说，我来给我们榨点新鲜橙汁。
So let's take a look at this verb, squeeze.
那我们来看看这个动词，“榨”。
To squeeze.
榨。
This is something you usually do with your hand when you tighten something.
这通常是你用手拧紧某物时做的动作。
So for example, your toothpaste.
比如，你的牙膏。
Yes, you squeeze your toothpaste so the toothpaste will come out.
是的，你挤牙膏，这样牙膏就会出来。
So in this case, we are squeezing the orange juice to extract the juice.
所以在这里，我们是在榨橙汁来提取果汁。
That's right.
没错。
So you, you hold the orange very tight, you make the juice come out and then you have
所以你紧紧握住橙子，让果汁流出来，然后你就得到了
fresh squeezed orange juice.
鲜榨橙汁。
And this is different from orange juice you buy in a store.
这和你在商店买的橙汁不同。
Okay.
好的。
So you can say, I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
所以你可以说，我来给我们榨点新鲜橙汁。
That means you're going to make fresh orange juice.
这意味着你要做新鲜橙汁。
And this fresh orange juice that you make is called fresh squeezed orange juice.
而你做的这种新鲜橙汁叫做鲜榨橙汁。
Fresh squeezed.
鲜榨的。
You've probably seen this in the store, like some bottles, they say a hundred percent fresh
你可能在商店里见过，比如有些瓶子上写着“100%鲜榨橙汁”之类的。
squeezed orange juice or something.
鲜榨橙汁之类的。
Yeah, it's good for advertising.
是啊，这对广告有好处。
All right.
好了。
So very good.
所以非常好。
A lot of great, interesting phrases there.
这里有很多很棒、有趣的短语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue one last time?
我们最后再听一遍对话好吗？
Smells good.
闻起来真香。
What's for breakfast?
早餐吃什么？
Well, since we're getting up so late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
嗯，既然我们起得这么晚，我决定做一顿丰盛的早餐。
Nice brunch.
不错的早午餐。
Kind of.
差不多吧。
So I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs, some French toast and buttermilk pancakes.
所以我做了炒蛋和溏心蛋，一些法式吐司和酪乳煎饼。
Wow.
哇。
You really went all out.
你真是全力以赴了。
Did you make any coffee?
你煮咖啡了吗？
Yeah, just the way you like it.
煮了，就按你喜欢的口味。
I also put out some cereal and muesli if you feel like having something more light.
我还放了一些麦片和什锦麦片，如果你想吃得清淡点的话。
Looks good.
看起来不错。
I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
我来给我们榨点新鲜橙汁。
Get the jam and butter while you are in there.
你在那里的时候把果酱和黄油拿来。
Oh, and don't forget the syrup.
哦，别忘了糖浆。
All righty.
好的。
All right.
好了。
So talking about brunch and breakfast, what is your typical or ideal breakfast?
说到早午餐和早餐，你典型或理想的早餐是什么？
That's a hard question.
这是个很难的问题。
Breakfast is my favorite meal of the day.
早餐是我一天中最喜欢的一餐。
So I could eat breakfast, all kinds of breakfast anytime.
所以我随时都能吃早餐，各种早餐都行。
But one of my favorite kinds of breakfast is a Greek diner breakfast.
但我最喜欢的早餐之一是希腊式小餐馆早餐。
Greek diner.
希腊式小餐馆。
What does this have?
这有什么？
Well, we have a lot of diners or small restaurants that are very, very cheap and fast in America.
嗯，美国有很多非常便宜又快捷的小餐馆或小餐厅。
And this usually involves some scrambled eggs that are made with cheese and toast and potatoes
这通常包括用奶酪做的炒蛋、吐司、土豆、
and bacon and sausage and a coffee.
培根、香肠和一杯咖啡。
Wow.
哇。
Big breakfast.
丰盛的早餐。
Very big.
非常丰盛。
But delicious.
但很好吃。
Nice.
不错。
What's your favorite?
你最喜欢什么？
I also really, really like breakfast.
我也非常非常喜欢早餐。
And I actually like having places that you can have 24-hour a day breakfast.
而且我其实喜欢那些能24小时提供早餐的地方。
All day breakfast is called.
这叫做全天早餐。
So I can have breakfast for dinner.
所以我可以晚餐吃早餐。
Right.
对。
That's usually in America, you go to a diner because they have breakfast at four o'clock
在美国，你通常会去小餐馆，因为他们凌晨四点或晚上七点都有早餐。
in the morning or at seven o'clock at night.
凌晨四点或晚上七点。
I'm not really a coffee person.
我不是一个爱喝咖啡的人。
I actually enjoy either juice, orange juice, or hot chocolate.
我其实喜欢果汁、橙汁或热巧克力。
I really like hot chocolate.
我真的很喜欢热巧克力。
And definitely pancakes.
而且绝对要有煎饼。
Three buttermilk pancakes stacked.
三个酪乳煎饼叠在一起。
And as you said before, syrup.
就像你之前说的，糖浆。
But I actually also put butter on it.
但我其实还在上面抹了黄油。
Gross.
真恶心。
I know a lot of people who do that.
我知道很多人会这么做。
They put butter on first and then they pour the syrup.
他们先抹黄油，然后再倒糖浆。
Yeah, of course.
是啊，当然。
So it's like complete, very, very fatty.
所以这简直是一份完整、非常非常油腻的早餐。
And hash browns.
还有土豆煎饼。
I'm definitely a fan of hash browns.
我绝对是土豆煎饼的粉丝。
Those are potatoes that are chopped very, very finely and you fry them together.
那些是把土豆切得非常非常细，然后一起煎炸的东西。
So it almost becomes like a potato pancake.
所以它几乎变成了像土豆饼一样的东西。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
So a lot of great stuff.
所以有很多好东西。
And obviously, breakfasts around the world are different.
显然，世界各地的早餐都不一样。
I know, for example, in some countries, they have the fisherman's breakfast.
我知道，比如在一些国家，他们有渔夫早餐。
So in the morning, you have black coffee, rice, and fish.
所以早上，你会喝黑咖啡、吃米饭和鱼。
That's right.
没错。
Because you're going to work all day.
因为你要工作一整天。
So we're really curious about how breakfast is in your country.
所以我们很好奇你们国家的早餐是什么样的。
What a typical breakfast is like.
典型的早餐是什么样的。
Yeah, what are traditional breakfasts and what is your favorite breakfast?
是啊，传统的早餐是什么，你最喜欢的早餐又是什么？
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们吧。
We hope to see you there.
我们期待在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
Bye.
再见。
I mean, we have good up-to-date advertising.
我是说，我们有最新的广告。